## BHANU DOBRIYAL

bhanudobriyal3@gmail.com | (607)232-8641 | 4325 Arques Ave, Round Rock, Texas, 78681 | linkedin.com/in/bhanudobriyal | github.com/bhanudobriyal | https://www.bhanudobriyal.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Resourceful professional offering about 3 years of experience providing software and web development solutions to clients utilizing an array of technology and software programs. A recent computer science engineering graduate, adept at formulating processes and leading teams in achieving excellence in client satisfaction, productivity, and profitability.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Developer | Tata Consultancy Services - Travelport (Client)**

November 2017 - January 2019

- Supported application enhancement of 3 **dot.net** framework based, C# coded applications. Only point of contact for these applications handling support, enhancements, and fixes
- Resolved an age-old bug within 1 month of taking over lead of the fix, by analyzing end to end flow of the application and working regularly with Test team to test and deploy update over production servers
- Developed User Interface using Javascript, HTML, CSS and Java for backend, for Hotel Availability Test Automation Tool, providing interactive user interface for client to test hotel availability, increasing service time by 30%
- · Trained and worked in an agile development methodology, participating in sprint planning, daily scrums and presenting sprint reviews to stakeholders

## **Technical Support Analyst | Tata Consultancy Services - British Telecom (Client)**

February 2016 - October 2017

- Led a team size of 6 other associates in order to get real time resolution of Tickets from BT Agent locations
- Created and Applied various workarounds, like tweaking of fulfilled, but stuck order XMLs thus resolving client service requests by upto 70%. Got various appreciation mails, e-cards from higher management for process improvement
- Worked on identifying and tagging PRs (Preventive Recurrences) numbers, so requisite fixes can be initiated in future releases, thus doing bulk resolutions and decreasing backlog by at-least 50%
- Presented a presentation to Client partners, SMEs at Gurugram client location and organized Knowledge transfer (KT) sessions between multiple teams across multiple vendors over weekly calls

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **MERN E-commerce website**

- Build an eCommerce platform from ground up with React, NodeJS, Express & MongoDb complete with user authentication, shopping cart, visible order history and editable product details
- Implemented the PayPal Sandbox API for live transactions and deployed web app over cloud using Heroku

## Live Video Streaming and Chat Web Application

- · Created a Full Stack web application with real-time Video and Chat features among multiple users, through HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Socket.IO library
- Deployed it over Google Cloud Platform using Docker and enabled auto-scaling features through Kubernetes

## **Design Patterns in Java**

- Multi-Threaded Merge sort using Singleton Design Pattern
- Searched a technical sentence with help of word from input files through Visitor Pattern

## Sentiment Analysis over Tweets based of Hashtag classification

- Research project build utilizing Python, MongoDb database to retrieve tweets based on different Hashtags over 3 months
- Analyzed associated sentiments implementing Natural Language Processing (NLP) python libraries and plot graphs to show any changes or relationships among tags

## **Uniform Resource Locator (URL) shortener**

Developed single page application on JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, Express, Axios, Mustache and MongoDB database

## **EDUCATION**

Master in Science, Computer Science Binghamton University, SUNY | Watson School of Engineering & Applied Science

January 2019 - December 2020

Data Structures and Algorithms, Design Patterns, Programming for the Web, Cloud Computing, Programming Languages, Computer Organization and Architecture, Operating Systems, Data Science in Social Media, Software Engineering Project management

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering Shri Mata Vaishno Devi University, Katra, India

August 2011 - May 2015

# **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages:** Core Java, J2EE, Python, C, C++, C# (.NET)

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, jQuery, NodeJS, ExpressJS, jQuery, Spring MVC, MongoDB, MySQL,

Microsoft SQL Server, RESTful webservices, SQAP, Apache HTTP Server, Tomcat, SoapUI, DBViewer

Cloud Technologies: Google Cloud Platform, Docker, Kubernetes, Heroku, AWS

Integrated development environment: Eclipse, Microsoft Visual Studio, NetBeans, IntelliJ IDEA, WebStorm

Other Tools and Softwares: Jupyter Notebook, Jira, ServiceNow, Git, Apache Subversion, JSON, XML, SharePoint

Certifications: Certified SAFe 4 Practitioner